

CRM/OPERATIONS COORDINATOR-EXPERT IN LAST MILE

Details

Cholayil House, Palakkad District, Kerala-678632 9072503235 nisha.cm14@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH 14-03-1994

NATIONALITY

Indian

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Communication Skills

Fast Learner

Leadership and Teamwork

Operations& Project Implementation

Key customer Handling

Business Development

Languages

English

Hindi

Malayalam

Tamil

Profile

Heading CRM and Operations with 7 years of experience in Logistics Industry. Proven success in leadership, operational excellence and organizational development with keen understanding of elements of E-Commerce and Logistic business. Recognized for inspiring team members to excel and encouraging creative work environments. Having good knowledge in new changes and evolution which is happening within the industry.

Employment History

Dept Head-Delivery Management Cell at Trackon Couriers Pvt Ltd, Cochin

DECEMBER 2020 — NOVEMBER 2022

Dealing with RO operations and hub operations, Handling more than 44 Branches and 150+ Franchises.

- Heading all Kerala B2B and B2C Operations. Handling a team size of 300 + members, this Include Managers and supervisors of 44 Branches and 150+ Franchisees.
- Complete Responsibility of station operations including Inbound/Outbound Operations and reverse pickups in day to day activity.
- Continuously review existing work practices and process flows within operations to identify qualitative improvement opportunities.
- Manage and lead a group of employees in the location to ensure work discipline. Setting strategic plans/operational goals and monitoring the team performance.
- Evaluate service levels, review processes and procedures, identify areas for improvement, and establish and execute action plans.
- Liaising with multiple teams such as sales, finance and customer service for smooth operations.
- Experience in managing critical operational processes, with SLA responsibility.
- Setting up KRAs & KPIs and Evaluate process performance & strategy progress, action plans on areas for improvement, and monitoring customer complaint and its resolution.
- Assign,monitor & review of individual performance as per KRA & Develop plan for performance improvement requirement.
- Performance analysis of branches and franchisees and reporting the same to HO.

CRM Manager at Trackon couriers Pvt Ltd, Cochin.

AUGUST 2018-DECEMBER 2020

- Key Customer visit- Driving the weekly conference calls as well as quarterly on-site meetings with customers for identifying and addressing issues and concerns.
- Build professional and productive relationships with clients.
- Complete responsibility of a regional CRM team.
- Inspecting complaints and resolving them in a timely and reasonable manner.
- MIS Report Presentation and Generation.
- Monitoring of Key clients Delivery Performance, Transit Time and NSLs.
- Carry out Monthly/quarterly formal reviews with the customer.

- Responsible for employee engagement. Lead the team to achieve best-in-class customer service. Set clear objectives and guide team to achieve targets and performance standards.
- Act as a prime point of contact with customers, working closely with Regional Sales Manager and Operations Manager to deliver seamless customer experience.
- Also a member of a dedicated management team for resolving critical issues in customer relations, such as payments, contracts, and executive-level complaints.

Administration and Customer Relations at Recahon Fastbuz (Ajoint venture of KSRTC-Trackon couriers Pvt Ltd)

OCTOBER 2015-AUGUST 2018

- Organize and maintenance of franchises and its staffs of Kerala Region .
- Organize branding of the company and service.
- Partner with HR to update and maintain office policies as necessary.
- · Organize office operations and procedure.
- Ensure that all items are invoiced and paid on time.
- Manage contract and price negotiations with office vendors, service providers and office lease - Address employees queries regarding office management issues (e.g. stationery, Hardware and travel arrangements) -Liaise with facility management vendors, including cleaning, catering and security services.
- Plan in-house or off-site activities, like parties, celebrations and conferences.

Education

MBA- Human Resource Management , Bharathiar University, Coimbatore 2019-2021

Bachelor of Computer Application, Bharathiar University, Coimbatore 2014-2016

Diploma Engineering-Computer Hardware Maintenance, Board of Technical Education, Kerala, Palakkad

2011 — 2014

Achievements

Project Implementation-Reachon fastbuz, Cochin

2015 - 2018

Worked as Admin at Reachon fastbuz- A unique collaboration between Trackon couriers Pvt Ltd and KSRTC to provide the fastest courier service in Kerala.